FAROUK AHMED

Nairobi, Kenya | thiaqoacookie@qmail.com | www.faroukahmed.com

PROFILE

I'm a self taught frontend developer from Nairobi, Kenya with a passion for web development. I have 1 year of experience, I'm a good colleague who loves getting the best out of everyone I'm working with. Also, I'm fluent in English and Kiswahili is my Native Language. I'm keen to pursue a career in web development with a focus on the frontend part of it.

SKILLS

Languages
Javascript, HTML, CSS and React
Frameworks and Libraries
Bootstrap, Next Js and Sass
Technologies
Git and Wordpress

EXPERIENCE

Freelance software developer. January 2022 - Present

Currently working on exciting freelance projects with clients globally which is helping me solidify my skills and making me gain valuable experience. (HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Next Js, Bootstrap and Sass).

Software Developer and Digital Marketing - Amazon Cellular (Nairobi, Kenya). June 2020 - December 2021

Implemented the layout and functionality of an ecommerce web app . The web app was integrated with Google Analytics and Facebook Pixel which were useful in selling electronics countrywide (Kenya) which I was handling too.(HTML, CSS, Javascript Bootstrap and Sass)

EDUCATION

Railway Training Institute. Feb 2019 - July 2021